<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Raleigh Real Estate Podcast with Terrence Boykin</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Boykin Realty Associates - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Terrence Boykin</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-06-15 15:20:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Terrence Boykin</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Terrence@RaleighsBestAgent.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Terrence Boykin</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Raleigh Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Boykin Realty Associates - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Real Estate FAQ's Answered</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-real-estate-faqs-answered.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-12 14:50:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/5+Real+Estate+FAQ's+Answered.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The following are the five most frequently asked questions we receive in the real estate industry:

1. “Why are the real estate prices in Raleigh so high?”

There are a few reasons for that. The first is the education level. As you know, we have NC State, Duke, UNC, and several other universities in the area, which drives our prices up. Secondly, we’re located about two hours from the coast and four hours from the mountains. The third reason is that we’re halfway between New York and Florida—so you can thank the Yankees for running our house prices up!

2. “Am I going to be renting forever?”

That depends—are you ‘renting’ your parents’ basement? If so, you may never move out. However, if you do want to move out, you really only need to have enough money saved up for closing costs. There are several loan programs that can get you into a house without paying a down payment. I recommend that everyone buy real estate; even when I talk to prospective Realtors, I tell them to get their licenses and start buying real estate as soon as they can.

“We might have some ups and downs in our transactions, but at the end of the day, my clients are happy—and that’s why I love what I do.”

3. “Why do Realtors hate Zillow?”

Not all Realtors hate Zillow—it can be a great tool. But yes, some Realtors do hate Zillow, though many of those Realtors are the kind who can’t operate an electronic lockbox. The automated home value that Zillow gives homeowners, while not necessarily accurate, can be a great conversation starter between me and a consumer. Zillow has never been in your house; they don’t know what views or upgrades your home has. I can then show that person exactly what their house is worth.

4. “Are Realtors rich?”

This is one of the biggest misconceptions about real estate—I know because I just checked my bank account. The rich Realtors you see on TV are probably in the top one-hundredth of the top 1% of all Realtors.

5. “What do Realtors do all day?”

In most offices, not a whole lot. The great Realtors will spend a large part of their day viewing houses and taking notes on the market so that when we sit down with you, you can be confident in the numbers we put in front of you. Another thing that I enjoy about real estate is that every day is different from the day before. 

I hope these answers helped you understand a little bit more about real estate. If you have any further questions or suggestions for future topics for me to address, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/5+Real+Estate+FAQ's+Answered.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/5+Real+Estate+FAQ's+Answered.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m going to answer the five most-asked questions about real estate.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m going to answer the five most-asked questions about real estate.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Ensure Business Growth After the Pandemic’s Over</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-ensure-business-growth-after-the-pandemics-over.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-20 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+to+Ensure+Business+Growth+After+the+Pandemics+Over.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Jeff Cochran from Exclamation Communications joined me recently to answer the question, “How do business owners pivot out of the coronavirus pandemic?” Jeff and his team have done some great work with us on re-branding during this time, and we’re excited to come out of this period with a fresh look. We talked about what Jeff does, what he’s helped us with, and what advice he has for business owners who are considering a pivot. To learn more, watch our latest video above.

Contact Jeff Cochran at 410-292-7194 or by visiting his website https://www.eci-design.com/
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+to+Ensure+Business+Growth+After+the+Pandemics+Over.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+to+Ensure+Business+Growth+After+the+Pandemics+Over.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how you can re-energize your business when restrictions are lifted.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how you can re-energize your business when restrictions are lifted.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Will It Be a New House or a New Spouse?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/will-it-be-a-new-house-or-a-new-spouse.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-08 12:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/A+Few+Ways+to+Profit+From+Your+Additional+Free+Time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Most of us have regularly scheduled maintenance appointments, but do you take the time to regularly check up on your assets and finances? Right now is a great time to do that. Insurance policies are a great place to start. One client I spoke to last week was able to reduce his homeowners insurance by almost half just by calling around and asking for quotes. It’s also a great time to take an inventory of your belongings. To learn more about what else you can do during this time of quarantine to save you time and money when this is all over, watch this short video above.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/A+Few+Ways+to+Profit+From+Your+Additional+Free+Time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/A+Few+Ways+to+Profit+From+Your+Additional+Free+Time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Most of us have a lot more free time right now than we’re used to. Here’s how to use that free time to your advantage financially.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Most of us have a lot more free time right now than we’re used to. Here’s how to use that free time to your advantage financially.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Difference Between a Custom Builder and Tract Builder?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-difference-between-a-custom-builder-and-tract-builder.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-26 16:12:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Whats+the+Difference+Between+a+Custom+Builder+and+Tract+Builder_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are the main differences between custom builders and tract builders.

What’s the difference between a custom builder and a tract builder? 

A custom builder is exactly what it sounds like—a builder who can customize your home plan so that it functions perfectly for your family. They may offer thousands of plans to choose from. They can even combine plans for your home to make sure it’s perfect. They’ll normally build in one or two subdivisions at a time, or on a vacant lot for an individual builder. Most custom builders build less than 50 houses per year.  

A tract (or production) builder, on the other hand, buys large tracts of land and divides them into smaller lots for individual home sales. They’ll have a handful of home plans available for each subdivision. Tract builders can be local or national, and some of the larger national builders can build thousands of homes per year. 

“For both types of builders, the average build time is between six and 12 months.”

The biggest difference between these two builders is their number of available lots. If you work with a tract builder, you’ll have hundreds of choices within a single subdivision. That same builder may also have upwards of 10 other subdivisions in the same area you can choose from. As stated above, custom builders would only be building in one or two communities, and you can also have the build on an individual lot you’ve purchased outside of a subdivision.  

The second biggest difference lies in the number of available floor plans. Working with a tract builder means only having about five to 10 home plans to choose from in each subdivision. This can be a good thing, though, because it means you’re less likely to blow your budget in the design center and/or be overwhelmed by all the choices since the home isn’t truly personalized. 

The last main difference between each builder is their build time. If you build with a custom builder, your build will last about two months longer than it would with a tract builder because you’re actually designing the house. Designing the plan and getting the plan approved permit-wise is about a two-month process. For both types of builders, the average build time is between six and 12 months. 

If you have questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to call or email me. Have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Whats+the+Difference+Between+a+Custom+Builder+and+Tract+Builder_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Whats+the+Difference+Between+a+Custom+Builder+and+Tract+Builder_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are the main differences between custom builders and tract builders.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are the main differences between custom builders and tract builders.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How and Why Homes Are Still Selling During the Pandemic</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-and-why-homes-are-still-selling-during-the-pandemic.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-14 15:14:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+and+Why+Homes+Are+Still+Selling+During+the+Pandemic.mp4</guid>
        <description>

With the COVID-19 pandemic impacting all of our daily lives, the way we do business in real estate has changed too. People are still out there buying and selling homes in spite of the current situation, but they’re doing so digitally. Real estate economists predict about a 10% reduction in deals this spring, but that means that 90% of homes that would have sold anyway will still sell. To learn more about how we’re adapting to this situation, and how you can still buy or sell a home during the next few months, watch this short video above.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+and+Why+Homes+Are+Still+Selling+During+the+Pandemic.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+and+Why+Homes+Are+Still+Selling+During+the+Pandemic.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Homes are still selling during this pandemic, but in a different way. Here’s how we’re adapting.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Homes are still selling during this pandemic, but in a different way. Here’s how we’re adapting.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Investing During a Pandemic</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/real-estate-investing-during-a-pandemic.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-02 11:38:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What investments can you make during this global pandemic? Today I’m here with Matt Maiers from Hunter Street Investment Advisors to discuss this topic. Many people are seeing the volatility of the current stock market and want to invest in real estate instead. How can they do it? First, interest rates are at a 50-year low, so it’s a great time to look into this.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Many see the stock market’s unpredictability and want to invest in real estate instead. Today we’re telling you how you can do this, even during a pandemic.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Many see the stock market’s unpredictability and want to invest in real estate instead. Today we’re telling you how you can do this, even during a pandemic.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Coronavirus’s impact on the market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/coronaviruss-impact-on-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-26 09:08:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Coronaviruss+Impact+on+the+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Will your home still sell during the pandemic? How will the stock market plunge affect home prices? Can you meet with your real estate agent via video conference to maintain social distancing? Clients have several questions about how to move forward in real estate now that the coronavirus pandemic has changed so much about day-to-day life, and today I want to answer these questions to educate and put you at ease. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Coronaviruss+Impact+on+the+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Coronaviruss+Impact+on+the+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Will your home still sell during the pandemic?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Will your home still sell during the pandemic?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Coronavirus Will Impact Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-the-coronavirus-will-impact-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-06 14:21:24 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+the+Coronavirus+Will+Impact+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How will the coronavirus affect mortgage rates and ultimately your ability to afford a house? Find out today.

As you know, the coronavirus has had quite an impact on the stock market, and in turn, we’ve seen interest rates take a huge drop. Over the last two or three days (as of this recording), rates have fallen significantly. Before the outbreak of the virus, rates were already as low as they’d ever been, but now they’re even lower.

This is great for many homebuyers, who will see increased buying power and lower monthly payments because of it. If you’re thinking about moving up, for example, now is the time. You could also take advantage of the times by taking cash out of your home; home values have increased significantly lately. Or, if you have mortgage insurance and you want to refinance, doing so now can reduce your rate and get rid of your PMI.

“If there is a large outbreak, however, that could have a negative impact on the housing market.”

If the coronavirus sticks around for a while, what’s the outlook for the market?

If the virus is short-lived and able to be contained, we’ll be able to enjoy these low rates for a bit longer. If there is a large outbreak, however, that could have a negative impact on the housing market. Since we’re not sure what the future will look like, Michelle recommends taking advantage of the low rates by buying or refinancing now.

Speaking of refinancing, if you’ve bought a home in the last four or five years, I recommend giving Michelle a call. She can help you determine whether refinancing your home to save money each month makes sense given your situation. The lowest credit rating she can work with is 580 for an FHA loan, 600 for a VA loan, 620 for conventional, and 640 for USDA loans. The higher your credit score, the better interest rates for which you’ll qualify.

If you have any questions about lending, contact Michelle at (919) 796-3097 or visit www.MichelleLendsMoney.com. For your other real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to the Boykin Realty Associations. We’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+the+Coronavirus+Will+Impact+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/How+the+Coronavirus+Will+Impact+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How will the coronavirus affect mortgage rates and ultimately your ability to afford a house? Find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How will the coronavirus affect mortgage rates and ultimately your ability to afford a house? Find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 5 Steps of the New Home Construction Process</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-5-steps-of-the-new-home-construction-process.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-13 08:47:37 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/The+5+Steps+of+the+New+Home+Construction+Process.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is the process of building a new home? Today I’ll break it down for you.

Are you dissatisfied with your current home’s layout or just ready to live in something new? If so, you’ve probably considered having a new home built for you. How does this process go? Today I’ve broken the new home construction process down into five steps:

1. Choose the right floor plan. There are many other factors to consider when it comes to choosing the layout of new construction homes.  Do you want a master bedroom upstairs or downstairs? Do you need a formal dining room or will an eat-in kitchen suffice? Do you plan to entertain guests with mobility restrictions? Consider these questions before you settle on a floor plan. 

2. Meet with the builder. Have a conversation with the builder to tailor your home to your family’s needs. For example, you can request a downstairs powder room, a larger pantry, or a specific number of bedrooms. You’ll also get to pick how the outside of the home looks. Decide on all these changes up front before the builder sends the design to the architect; if you make changes after the architect and engineer have approved it, you’ll be charged a fee.

3. Choose the trim, hardware, and paint. Usually, this is done by meeting with the builder at their design center. These meetings take about four hours with a custom build, so you may want to schedule this as two meetings since there will be more decisions to make. Pin down your budget beforehand so that you know exactly what you’ll be able to spend and don’t break the bank.

“If the builder doesn’t have the perfect plan for you, shop around for other builders before you sell your current home.”

4. Begin construction. Once the design has been approved by the architect and engineer and the builder has gotten a building permit, the construction of your new home will start. You’ll have at least four meetings with the builder during this process:


  A pre-construction meeting where you’ll visit the site, review the basic layout, and learn the build timeline.
  A drywall meeting where the builder will show you the things you don’t normally see because of sheetrock; you’ll also make sure that everything is where it should be.
  A blue-tape meeting where you’ll go through the house a week before closing to apply blue tape to any imperfections you see; by the closing date, those issues should have been addressed.


5. Move-in day. Before you close, you’ll meet with the builder to check whether the blue-tape items you marked were replaced or repaired. You’ll also go through all the systems of the house to learn all the works. As long as everything at this stage checks out, you’re clear to close on the home.

A year after you close on your new construction home, you’ll have one more meeting with the builder where they come back to repair any issues that have arisen with the construction of the house since you bought it. Most builders offer a one-year warranty.

If you have any further questions about the process of building a new home or real estate in general, feel free to call, text, or email us here at Boykin Realty Associates. We’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/The+5+Steps+of+the+New+Home+Construction+Process.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/The+5+Steps+of+the+New+Home+Construction+Process.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the process of building a new home? Today I’ll break it down for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the process of building a new home? Today I’ll break it down for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Predictions for Triangle Real Estate in 2020</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-predictions-for-triangle-real-estate-in-2020.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-28 09:22:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Our+Predictions+for+Triangle+Real+Estate+in+2020.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does the 2020 market year have in store for buyers and sellers in the Triangle area?

What can we expect from real estate in the Triangle area now that we’ve begun the new year? Here are our predictions for what’s to come, as well as our advice for buyers and sellers who plan to act in the market this year:

We do expect the housing shortage to continue, which will lead to a continued rise in home prices. The appreciation rate will likely be around 5% in 2020, which is a little lower than previous years but still great for our sellers.

With the new year upon us, we see people beginning to focus on their list of goals, and real estate usually contends for the top spots in those lists. When crafting your goals, it’s best to be prepared so that you can pull the trigger at a moment’s notice. So if you’re planning to sell your house in April or May, it’s a good idea to start fixing things up now so that your house is clean and ready to go.

“Ask your agent what strategies they can use to ensure that your family will only have to move once.”

It’s also a good time to start interviewing real estate agents. Ask them what recommendations they have for getting your home in peak condition. Here at Boykin Realty Associates, we offer a two-hour staging consultation with an interior decorator. This helps take the stress out of preparing your home for the market.

The next issue to consider is where you’re going to live. Since inventory is so tight in the area, you’ll need to plan ahead for your next move. Ask your agent what strategies they can use to ensure that your family will only have to move once. It’s also a good idea to ask if there are any contingencies they can put in place should issues arise on either the buying or the selling side of the transaction.

The spring market is set to come early this year. If you’re a buyer, reach out to a lender to find out exactly how much home you can afford. We have a huge shortage of homes below the $300,000 price point, so make sure that you get pre-approved in advance to eliminate certain barriers to your next purchase. Ask your real estate agent about their average days on market, their list-to-sales price ratio, and the average amount of seller-paid contingencies in your area. These numbers will tell you if your Realtor can negotiate the best deal for you and your family.

If you have any questions about real estate in 2020, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Our+Predictions+for+Triangle+Real+Estate+in+2020.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/Our+Predictions+for+Triangle+Real+Estate+in+2020.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What does the 2020 market year have in store for buyers and sellers in the Triangle area?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What does the 2020 market year have in store for buyers and sellers in the Triangle area?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Biggest Mistakes Home Sellers Make?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-biggest-mistakes-home-sellers-make.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Terrence Boykin</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-13 10:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/What+Are+the+Biggest+Mistakes+Home+Sellers+Make_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Home sellers are susceptible to making a wide variety of mistakes. Here are the six most important ones that should be avoided.

Now that we’ve passed the holiday season, I’m hearing from a lot of prospective home sellers about what they can do to their home to make sure it sells fast. To do this, it’s important to also avoid the common pitfalls that doom other sellers. If you follow these simple guidelines, the process will be as stress-free as possible. Do everything you can to avoid making the following mistakes:

1. Picking the wrong agent. You want an agent who will return your calls, get back to you promptly, and answer your questions. The agent should know the houses in your area because they are the local real estate expert. The right agent will be honest and straightforward with you. They won’t just tell you what you want to hear.

2. Overpricing your home. Price is one of the biggest issues when selling a home. The more realistically priced we are, the quicker your home will sell.

“Buyers don’t want to see clutter online.”

3. Failing to make simple repairs. You know the ones I’m talking about. Whether it’s a dog that has chewed something or a carpet stain that the buyer will see immediately, you want to repair any minor damages before putting the house on the market.

4. Neglecting to declutter your home. Buyers are looking at the home online. If they’re seeing clutter instead of rooms, there is less chance that they’ll come to see the house in person. Store your clutter in the garage or a storage unit so nothing gets in the way of your pictures and showings.

5. Not allowing adequate access to your home. For every 10 buyers that can’t get in to see a home when they want, about eight of them never reschedule. I know this can be a stressful time, but your home needs to be show-ready when agents need to see it, not just when it’s convenient for you.

6. Emotional attachment to the home. This is understandable, especially if you’ve raised your family in the home. However, when it’s time to list, you need to see the home as an investment and an asset. There will be lowball offers, but you have to be okay with that. The goal is to get as much money as possible for you on the sale of your home.

If you have further questions about this list or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/What+Are+the+Biggest+Mistakes+Home+Sellers+Make_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Terrence+Boykin/What+Are+the+Biggest+Mistakes+Home+Sellers+Make_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Home sellers are susceptible to making a wide variety of mistakes. Here are the six most important ones that should be avoided.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Terrence Boykin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Home sellers are susceptible to making a wide variety of mistakes. Here are the six most important ones that should be avoided.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Terrence Boykin</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Terrence Boykin</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Boykin Realty Associates - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
